<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-08-19T11:08:07+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The 34th Meeting of Computational Linguistics in The Netherlands</title><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><entry><title type="html">Registration deadline extended</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/14/registration-deadline-extended/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Registration deadline extended" /><published>2024-08-14T13:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-08-14T13:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/08/14/registration-deadline-extended</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/08/14/registration-deadline-extended/"><![CDATA[<div>
 The deadline for registration to CLIN34 has been extended until <b>21 August 2024</b>. Click <a href="/2024/07/05/registration-open/">here</a> to register. After registration, you will receive a link to the online payment system. The conference fee is 65 euros and includes lunch, coffee breaks, and closing drinks. Your registration is considered complete only after filling out the form and completing payment. <b>Please use the same name in this form and the online payment system.</b>
</div>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="abstracts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The deadline for registration to CLIN34 has been extended until 21 August 2024. Click here to register.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Registrations to CLIN34 are open</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/05/registration-open/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Registrations to CLIN34 are open" /><published>2024-07-05T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-05T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/07/05/registration-open</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/07/05/registration-open/"><![CDATA[<div>
Registrations to CLIN34 are open until 21 August 2024. Click <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1k6OIpiuQNGu_xGr6X7opxAI1pdDm0F2S1-Ujx0KO1zA">here</a> to register. After registration, you will receive a link to the online payment system. The conference fee is 65 euros and includes lunch, coffee breaks, and closing drinks. Your registration is considered complete only after filling out the form and completing payment. <b>Please use the same name in this form and the online payment system.</b>
</div>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="abstracts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Registrations to CLIN34 are open. Click here to register. Please note that registration closes on 15 August 2024.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accepted abstracts for CLIN 34</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/15/accepted-abstracts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accepted abstracts for CLIN 34" /><published>2024-06-15T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-15T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/06/15/accepted-abstracts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/06/15/accepted-abstracts/"><![CDATA[<style>
        body {
            font-family: Arial, sans-serif;
            margin: 0;
            padding: 0;
        }
        table {
            width: 100%;
            /* border-collapse: collapse; */
            margin-top: 0px;
            margin-bottom: 0px;
            display: table-cell;
        }
        h1 {
            margin-bottom: 10px;
        }
        th, td {
            border: 1px solid #ddd;
            padding: 8px;
            text-align: left;
        }
        th {
            background-color: #001158;
            color: white;
        }
        .name-column {
            min-width: 250px;
        }
        .aff-column {
            min-width: 300px;
        }
        .title-column {
            min-width: 300px;
        }
        .containers {
            margin: 0;
            display: table;
        } 

    </style>

<div class="containers">
        <table>
            <thead>
                <tr><th class="name-column">Name(s)</th>
                    <th class="aff-column">Affiliation(s)</th>
                    <th class="title-column">Abstract Title</th></tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
                <tr><td>Shantanu Nath</td><td>University of Trento</td><td>EVALUATION OF COREFERENCE MODELS ON DIFFERENT DOMAINS AND TEXT GENRES</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Hyewon Jang <br /> Diego Frassinelli</td><td>University of Konstanz <br /> University of Konstanz, Center for Information and Language Processing at LMU Munich</td><td>Detecting sarcasm using LLMs when sarcasm is way too broad</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Behnaz Motavali</td><td>Radboud University</td><td>Written by one: Common authorship features of Fake Job Posts</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Esther Ploeger <br /> Wessel Poelman <br /> Andreas Holck Høeg-Petersen <br /> Anders Schlichtkrull <br /> Miryam de Lhoneux <br /> Johannes Bjerva</td><td>Aalborg University <br /> KU Leuven <br /> Aalborg University <br /> Aalborg University <br /> KU Leuven <br /> Aalborg University</td><td>Leveraging Linguistic Typology for Fairer Multilingual Language Technology</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Colin Swaelens <br /> Ilse De Vos <br /> Els Lefever</td><td>LT3, Ghent University, Belgium <br /> VAIA - Flanders AI Academy <br /> LT3, Ghent University, Belgium</td><td>Similarity Detection in Medieval Marginal Writing</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Xinnain Zhao <br /> Hugo Van Hamme</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Weakly and Semi-supervised Training of Flemish ASR from Subtitles</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Leonidas Mylonadis <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam; Data Science Centre, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Evaluation of Greek Word Embeddings</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Maya Sappelli <br /> Laura Meijer <br /> Marije Vrijmoeth <br /> Dianne Teunisse <br /> Annette Klarenbeek</td><td>HAN University of Applied Sciences <br /> University of Applied Sciences Utrecht <br /> University of Applied Sciences Utrecht <br /> University of Applied Sciences Utrecht <br /> University of Applied Sciences Utrecht</td><td>Automatic Detection of Discursive Patterns in Dutch Social Media</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Baoyi Zeng <br /> Leonidas A. A. Doumas</td><td>Faculty of Engineering Science, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium <br /> School of Philosophy, Psychology, and Language Sciences, The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK</td><td>lllusion of Plausibility with Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Bram Groenhof <br /> Wieke Harmsen <br /> Helmer Strik</td><td>Radboud University</td><td>On the possibility of using pre-trained ASR-models to assess oral reading exams automatically</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Janiça Hackenbuchner <br /> Aaron Maladry <br /> Arda Tezcan <br /> Joke Daems</td><td>Ghent University</td><td>Systematic, Stereotypical or an Educated Guess? Gender inference by humans and machine translation systems of words in and out of context</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Natalia Evgrafova <br /> Véronique Hoste <br /> Els Lefever</td><td>LT3, Ghent University</td><td>Identifying Controversial Claims in Political YouTube Comments</td></tr>                
                <tr><td>Goya van Boven <br /> Yupei Du <br /> Dong Nguyen</td><td>Utrecht University</td><td>Transforming Dutch: Debiasing Dutch Coreference Resolution Systems for Non-binary Pronouns</td></tr>                
                <tr><td>Mario Perez Eguiluz</td><td>TNO; Leiden University</td><td>Evaluating User trust for the FarmBuddy chatbot: a mixed methods study</td></tr>                
                <tr><td>Xander Snelder</td><td>University of Amsterdam</td><td>Evaluating the Intrinsic Effects of Prompt Engineering: The Indirect Extraction of Semantic Similarities from GPTs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Gus Lathouwers <br /> Helmer Strik <br /> Wieke Harmsen <br /> Catia Cucchiarini</td><td>Radboud University</td><td>Examining Boundaries: Recontextualizing Dutch Syllabification Algorithms</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Tess Dejaeghere <br /> Pranaydeep Singh <br /> Bas Vercruysse <br /> Julie Birkholz <br /> Els Lefever</td><td>Ghent Center for Digital Humanities, Ghent University; LT3, Ghent University <br /> LT3, Ghent University <br /> Ghent Center for Digital Humanities, Ghent University <br /> Ghent Center for Digital Humanities, Ghent University <br /> LT3, Ghent University</td><td>Exploring Zero-Shot Named Entity Recognition in Multilingual Historical Travelogues Using Open-Source Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Matthijs Westera <br /> Mark Rademaker</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Can we detect the need-for-closure bias in social media behavior?</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Kyo Gerrits <br /> Ana Guerberof Arenas</td><td>University of Groningen</td><td>Reader reception of computational literary translations: the question of creativity.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Stef Accou <br /> Tim Van de Cruys</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Word Sense Discrimination using French Transformer Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Sander Puts <br /> Shashank Chakravarthy <br /> Martijn Nobel <br /> André L. A. J. Dekker <br /> Catharina M.L. Zegers <br /> Inigo Bermejo</td><td>Department of Radiation Oncology (Maastro), GROW Research Institute for Oncology and Reproduction, Maastricht University Medical Centre+</td><td>Improving Text Classification by Filtering Out Irrelevant Sentences Using a Sentence Classifier</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Joël Buter <br /> Joost Broekens <br /> Suzan Verberne</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Data Augmenting Dialogues for Improving Emotional Support Chatbots</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Hadi Mohammadi <br /> Anastasia Giachanou <br /> Ayoub Bagheri</td><td>Utrecht University</td><td>Enhancing Human-Likeness of Generative AI through Explainable Techniques</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Elena Savinova <br /> Jet Hoek</td><td>Centre for Language Studies, Radboud University</td><td>Interpreting Subjectivity Regressor Trained on Native English Speakers’ Judgments: Theory vs. Speaker Intuitions</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Mert Yazan <br /> Jirui Qi <br /> Xinyi Chen <br /> Andreas Paraskeva <br /> Yumeng Wang <br /> Mohanna Hoveyda </td><td>Leiden University <br /> University of Groningen <br /> University of Amsterdam <br /> Leiden University <br /> Leiden University <br /> Radboud University</td><td>Comprehensive Evaluation of RAG Pipelines in QA Systems: Insights from the CRAG Benchmark</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Pauline van Nies <br /> Marten Koopmans <br /> Gijs Wobben <br /> Coen Goedhart <br /> Paul Verhaar</td><td>Ordina; University of Applied Sciences Utrecht <br /> Ordina; University of Applied Sciences Utrecht <br /> Ordina <br /> Ordina <br /> Ordina; University of Applied Sciences Utrecht </td><td>Information Retrieval for Dutch Organizations: Evaluating Encoder Models and Practical Approaches</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Katrien Depuydt <br /> Jesse de Does <br /> Thomas Haga <br /> Roland de Bonth <br /> Tim Brouwer <br /> Vincent Prins <br /> Mathieu Fannee</td><td>Instituut voor de Nederlandse Taal</td><td>Towards better linguistic annotation for historical Dutch</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Julia Pestel <br /> Raquel G. Alhama</td><td>Institute for Logic, Language and Computation; University of Amsterdam</td><td>Evaluating the Linguistic Knowledge of Dutch Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Crit Cremers</td><td>Leiden University Centre for Linguistics</td><td>A view on propositions: graphics for meaningful parsing and generation</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Nadine Donia <br /> Weiwei Sun <br /> Arun Kumar Rajasekaran</td><td>École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne <br /> Cambridge University <br /> Cambridge University</td><td>Sentiment Analysis of Arabic-English Code-Switched Data: A Comparative Study of Machine Learning and Lexicon-Based Approaches</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Marije Kanis <br /> Marijn Schraagen <br /> Shihan Wang <br /> Erik Tjong Kim Sang</td><td>Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences <br /> Utrecht University <br /> Utrecht University <br /> Netherlands eScience Center</td><td>Happy or lonely? Investigating Dutch people’s mental well-being using remote methods during the COVID-19 pandemic</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Sidi Wang <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>Computational Linguistics and Text Mining Lab, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> Data Science Centre, University of Amsterdam; Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Quantifying Politicization: Leverage Contextualized Embeddings of Politicized Keywords</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Camille Lavigne <br /> Alex Stasica</td><td>Utrecht University</td><td>Automated Correction of Error Patterns in Dutch Child Speech: Leveraging Transformer Architecture for Enhanced Accuracy</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Lilit Kharatyan <br /> Frédéric Blain <br /> Gloria Corpas Pastor</td><td>Julius Maximilian University of Würzburg <br /> Tilburg University <br /> University of Malaga </td><td>Speech-to-Text Translation: Cascaded or End-to-end? Multidimensional Comparative Evaluation</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Simon Blanchard <br /> Walter Daelemans</td><td>University of Antwerp</td><td>On the generalisability of personality models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Qixiang Fang <br /> Javier Garcia Bernardo <br /> Erik-Jan van Kesteren</td><td>Utrecht University</td><td>Addressing LLM-related Measurement Error in Social Science Modeling Research</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Foteini Papadopoulou</td><td>Radboud University</td><td>Unveiling Sentiments and Topics in COVID-19 Vaccine Comments on YouTube Over Time: from the First Vaccine Approval to the Post-Pandemic Era</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Veronica Juliana Schmalz</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>The Strange Case of AI-generated and human-authored texts: A preliminary study comparing features from different levels of linguistic analysis and languages</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Pepijn Stoop <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Exploring Semantic Consistency in Zero-Shot Pre-trained Language Models for Emotion Detection Tasks in the Social Sciences and Humanities</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Jens Lemmens <br /> Walter Daelemans</td><td>University of Antwerp</td><td>Styloscope and Toposcope: Towards user-friendly digital text analysis</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Marzieh Abdolmaleki <br /> Véronique Hoste <br /> Els Lefever</td><td>LT3, Ghent University</td><td>Enhancing Update Statement Generation by Modeling Hypothesis Probability in Defeasible NLI</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Bram Vanroy <br /> Tim Van De Cruys</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Forced Creativity: Constrained Decoding to Generate Poetry With Any LLM</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Vincent Vandeghinste <br /> Job van Doeselaar <br /> Bram Vanroy</td><td>Instituut voor de Nederlandse Taal</td><td>Human Evaluation of Automated Text Simplification through Crowdsourcing</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Silvana Abdi <br /> Hylke Brouwer <br /> Martine Elzinga <br /> Shenza Gunput <br /> Sem Huisman <br /> Collin Krooneman <br /> David Poot <br /> Jelmer Top <br /> Cain Weideman <br /> Lisa Bylinina</td><td>University of Groningen</td><td>Dutch CoLA: Dutch grammatical knowledge in monolingual and multilingual language models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Florelien Soete <br /> Vincent Vandeghinste</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Optimizing Controllable Sentence Simplification for Dutch using T5 Large Language Model</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Florian Debaene <br /> Aaron Maladry  <br /> Pranaydeep Singh <br /> Els Lefever <br /> Veronique Hoste</td><td>LT3, Language and Translation Technology Team, Ghent University</td><td>Do we still need specialized transformers? A comparison to generative foundation models for non-normative Dutch</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Xiao Zhang <br /> Johan Bos</td><td>Center for Language and Cognition, University of Groningen</td><td>IconNet and Pictorial Meaning Representation: Towards Language-Neutral Semantics</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Congfeng Cao <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Linearly Mapping from Graph to Text Space</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Dragoș Alexandru Bălan</td><td>University of Twente</td><td>Evaluating the State-of-the-Art Automatic Speech Recognition systems for Dutch</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Sisi Chen <br /> Vincent Vandeghinste <br /> Goedele Vandommele</td><td>Department of Computer Science, KU Leuven <br />
Centre for Computational Linguistics, KU Leuven <br />
Centre for Language and Education, KU Leuven</td><td>Automated Pass/Fail Classification for Dutch as a Second Language Using Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>R. Kinds <br /> S. Abdi <br /> D. Timmer <br /> S. van Loon <br /> T. Caselli</td><td>University of Groningen</td><td>Watch Your Vocabulary More Than Your Pre-training Data</td></tr>
                <tr><td>I-Fan Lin <br /> Faegheh Hasibi <br /> Suzan Verberne</td><td>Leiden University <br /> Radboud University <br /> Leiden University</td><td>Generate then Refine: Data Augmentation for Zero-shot Intent Detection</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Nikki Rademaker <br /> Linthe van Rooij <br /> Yanna Smid <br /> Tessa Verhoef <br /> Tom Kouwenhoven</td><td>LIACS, Leiden University</td><td>The Riddle Experiment: two groups are trying to solve a black story behind a screen, only one group is alive.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Tanmay Khokle <br /> Tim Van de Cruys <br /> Kris Heylen</td><td>KU Leuven <br /> Centre for Computational Linguistics, KU Leuven <br /> Instituut voor de Nederlandse Taal</td><td>Multilingual Definition Modeling for Neologisms</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Rob Reijtenbach <br /> Gijs Wijnholds</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Dataset Generation for Visual Entailment using Generative AI</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Andriy Kosar <br /> Guy De Pauw <br /> Walter Daelemans</td><td>Textgain; CLiPS, University of Antwerp <br /> Textgain <br />
CLiPS, University of Antwerp</td><td>Evaluating LLM-Generated Topic Names via Text Reconstruction</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Svea Bösch <br /> Jelke Bloem <br /> Raquel Garrido Alhama</td><td>Amsterdam Center for Language and Communication, University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Amsterdam Center for Language and Communication, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Comparing the Impact of the Input Source in Modelling Child Language Acquisition</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Andrew Kosar <br /> Jens Van Nooten <br /> Walter Daelemans <br /> Guy De Pauw</td><td>University of Antwerp; Textgain <br /> University of Antwerp <br /> University of Antwerp <br /> Textgain</td><td>One Size Does Not Fit All: Exploring Variable Thresholds for Distance-Based Multi-Label Text Classification</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Katharina Sommer <br /> Evgeniia Egorova <br /> Eugene Shalugin</td><td>Radboud University</td><td>Domain adaptation of Large Language Models for Sparse Information Retrieval</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Zahra Abedi <br /> Gijs Wijnholds <br /> Richard van Dijk</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Enriching Historical Records: An OCR and AI-Driven Approach for Database Integration</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Urtė Jakubauskaitė <br /> Raquel G. Alhama <br /> Phong Le</td><td>Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Amazon Alexa</td><td>Compositionality in Emergent Languages: Evaluating the Metrics</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Lorenzo Lazzari <br /> Carlos Villacampa Calvo <br /> Sophia Katrenko</td><td>EcoVadis</td><td>Case Study: Leveraging Large Language Models in a Hybrid Search System for Improved CSR Information Retrieval</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Leonardo Grotti</td><td>CLiPS, University of Antwerp</td><td>Evaluating Grapheme-to-Phoneme Conversion and Syllable Counting of Large Language Models for Dutch</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Michelle Suijkerbuik <br /> Zoë Prins <br /> Marianne de Heer Kloots <br /> Willem Zuidema <br /> Stefan L. Frank</td><td>Centre for Language Studies, Radboud University <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Centre for Language Studies, Radboud University</td><td>BLiMP-NL: A corpus of Dutch minimal pairs and grammaticality judgements for language model evaluation</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Shima Rahimi <br /> Ehsan Lotfi <br /> Walter Daelemans</td><td>University of Antwerp</td><td>In-Corpus and Cross-Corpus Analysis of Native Language Identification Using Machine Learning</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Myrthe Reuver <br /> Indira Sen <br /> Gabriella Lapesa</td><td>Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> Universitat Konstanz <br /> GESIS - Leibniz-Institut für Sozialwissenschaften and Heinrich-Heine University Düsseldorf</td><td>A pilot study and framework for using and analyzing social scientist’s interaction strategies with Instruction-Tuned LLMs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Cristina Reguera-Gómez <br /> Denis Paperno <br /> Maaike H. T. de Boer</td><td>TNO; Utrecht University <br /> Utrecht University <br /> TNO</td><td>Natural Chatbots: Designing an Intuitive Healthcare Conversational Agent by Studying the Role of Empathy in Generated Messages</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Léa Gontard <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Using Natural Language Processing to Quantify Politicization in Foreign Aid Reports</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Matthew Micyk <br /> Jelke Bloem </td><td>Amsterdam Center for Language and Communication, University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Distributional Semantic Modeling of SC-Pair Polish Aspectual Verbs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ineke Schuurman <br /> Caro Brosens <br /> Kris Heylen <br /> Vincent Vandeghinste <br /> Bram Vanroy</td><td>Centrum voor Computerlinguïstiek, KU Leuven <br /> Vlaams GebarentaalCentrum <br /> Instituut voor de Nederlandse Taal <br /> Instituut voor de Nederlandse Taal <br /> Centrum voor Computerlinguïstiek, KU Leuven</td><td>WordNet-based Relations between Words, Signs and Concepts</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Michiel De Vrindt <br /> Anaïs Tack <br /> Renske Bouwer <br /> Wim Van Den Noortgate <br /> Marije Lesterhuis</td><td>imec research group ITEC, KU Leuven <br /> imec research group ITEC, KU Leuven <br /> Institute for Language Sciences, Utrecht University <br /> imec research group ITEC, KU Leuven <br /> Center for Research and Development of Health Professions Education, UMC Utrecht</td><td>Predicting Initial Quality Scores of Dutch Essays with Language Models to Warm-Start Comparative Judgment Assessments</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Loic De Langhe <br /> Orphée De Clercq <br /> Veronique Hoste</td><td>LT3, Ghent University</td><td>NewsBERTje: a Domain-Adapted Dutch BERT Model</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Qianru Meng <br /> Zhaochun Ren <br /> Joost Visser</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Automatic Release Notes Summarization with Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Wu Chi Hsiu <br /> Aaron Maladry <br /> Veronique Hoste</td><td>University of Antwerp <br /> LT3, Ghent University <br />
LT3, Ghent University</td><td>Comparing and Contrasting Modality Disparity in Multimodal Sarcasm Detection</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Aletta Dorst <br /> Alina Karakanta</td><td>Leiden University Centre for Linguistics, Leiden University</td><td>Comparing LLMs with commercial Machine Translation systems for Metaphor Translation</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Felicia Redelaar <br /> Suzan Verberne <br /> Maaike de Boer <br /> Romy van Drie</td><td>Leiden University; TNO <br /> Leiden University <br /> TNO <br /> TNO</td><td>Attributed Question Answering for the Dutch Law using Retrieval augmented Large language models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Chenglinzi Yang <br /> Jet Hoek <br /> Wilbert Spooren</td><td>Centre for Language Studies, Radboud University</td><td>Stance detection in conversational L1 and L2 English</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Simone van Bruggen <br /> Maaike Koninx</td><td>Bookarang, NBD Biblion</td><td>Ontology-based distance metrics for keyword evaluation</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Lisa Hubin</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Metaphorically speaking: a clustering-based exploration of metaphor identification in Dutch using transformer architectures</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Marthe Kellen <br /> Tim Van de Cruys</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Exploratory Study on Dutch Verb Clusters Using Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning: Evaluating Transformer Models’ Language Skills</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Suzan Lejeune <br /> Iris Hendrickx</td><td>Centre for Language Studies, Radboud University <br /> Centre for Language and Speech Technology, Radboud University</td><td>Location-focused Translation in Low-resource Tagalog of Flooding Events in News Articles</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Henry Grafé <br /> Tim Van de Cruys</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Multi-token and Multi-word Lexical Substitution using Encoder-Only Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Thijs Groeneweg <br /> Gijs Wijnholds</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Improving the CoThought pipeline for training a BabyLM on Dutch data</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Yumeng Wang <br /> Suzan Verberne</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Query-to-intent generation for explainable search engines</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Gabriella Bollici</td><td>TNO</td><td>Enhancing Human-Computer Interaction: Leveraging Miscommunication Detection in Chatbot Dialogues for Conversation Breakdown Prevention</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Urja Khurana <br /> Eric Nalisnick <br /> Antske Fokkens</td><td>Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> Johns Hopkins University <br /> Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam</td><td>Do Hate Speech Detection Models Reflect their Dataset’s Definition? Investigating Model Behavior on Hate Speech Aspects</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Wout Sinnaeve <br /> Joni Kruijsbergen <br /> Orphée De Clercq</td><td>Ghent University</td><td>Controlled Text Simplification for Dutch using Generative Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Michael Wheeler <br /> Suzan Verberne</td><td>LIACS, Leiden University</td><td>Retrieval augmented chatbot for an IT helpdesk (WIP)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Lea Krause <br /> Ana Valdivia</td><td>Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> University of Oxford</td><td>Exploring the Lack of Cultural Diversity in Multilingual Datasets for Conversational AI</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Kushal Tatariya <br /> Artur Kulmizev <br /> Esther Ploeger <br /> Marcell Bollman <br /> Jiaming Luo <br /> Johannes Bjerva <br /> Miryam de Lhoneux <br /> Heather Lent</td><td>KU Leuven <br /> KU Leuven <br /> Aalborg University <br /> Linköping University <br /> Google <br /> Aalborg University <br /> KU Leuven <br /> Aalborg University</td><td>How Good is Your Wikipedia? Quality Estimation and Methods of Data Pruning for Non-English Wikipedias</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Qixiang Fang <br /> Daniel Oberski <br /> Dong Nguyen</td><td>Utrecht University</td><td>PATCH -- Psychometrics-AssisTed benCHmarking of Large Language Models: A Case Study of Mathematics Proficiency</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Bram Vanroy</td><td>KU Leuven; Instituut voor de Nederlandse Taal</td><td>F(r)ietje: An efficient, transparent LLM for Dutch</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Allmin Susaiyah <br /> Natalia Sidorova</td><td>Eindhoven University of Technology</td><td>Towards the Extraction of Event Logs from Dutch Medical Reports Using Large Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Anum Afzal <br /> Alexandre Mercier <br /> Florian Matthes</td><td>Technical University of Munich</td><td>Investigating Data-to-Text Approaches to Achieve Diversity of Generated Marketing Text in the Music Industry</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ine Gevers <br /> Walter Daelemans</td><td>University of Antwerp</td><td>Bag of Lies: Robustness in Continuous Pre-training BERT</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Anna Wegmann <br /> Tijs van den Broek <br /> Dong Nguyen</td><td>Utrecht University <br /> Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> Utrecht University</td><td>What's Mine becomes Yours:  Defining, Annotating and Detecting  Context-Dependent Paraphrases in News Interview Dialogs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ho Wang Matthew Sung</td><td>Leiden University</td><td>Outliers or Wrong Classifications? On Dialect Typicality and Transitional Dialects</td></tr>
                <tr><td>David Shakouri</td><td>Leiden University Centre for Linguistics (LUCL), Leiden University; Leiden Institute for Brain and Cognition (LIBC), Leiden University</td><td>MODOMA: Providing a Computational Laboratory for Language Acquisition Experiments</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Roos M. Bakker <br /> Juul A. Schoevers <br /> Romy A.N. van Drie <br /> Marijn P. Schraagen <br /> Maaike H. T. de Boer</td><td>TNO; Leiden University <br /> TNO <br /> TNO <br /> Utrecht University <br /> TNO</td><td>Semantic Role Extraction in Law Texts: A Comparative Analysis of Language Models for Legal Information Extraction</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Marcel Haas <br /> Hielke Muizelaar <br /> Marco Spruit</td><td>Department of Public Health &amp; Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre <br /> Department of Public Health &amp; Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre <br /> LIACS, Leiden University</td><td> Exploring Translation's Impact on Dutch BERT Model Performance</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Xiyuan Gao <br /> Shekhar Nayak <br /> Matt Coler</td><td>Campus Fryslân, University of Groningen</td><td>Investigating the Multimodal Interplay of  Prosodic and Visual Cues of Sarcasm</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Olga Lyashevska <br /> Michael Giffin <br /> Samira van Bohemen</td><td>Netherlands eScience Center <br /> Erasmus School of Social and Behavioural Sciences, Erasmus University Rotterdam</td><td>On stereotypes in online pornography: the use of topic modelling.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Ine Gevers <br /> Cristina Arhiliuc <br /> Leonardo Grotti <br /> Pieter Fivez</td><td>University of Antwerp</td><td>Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) in Generative Large Language Models for Automated Essay Grading</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Wouter Hajer <br /> Anne Fleur van Luenen <br /> Jakob Söhl <br /> Rolf Ypma</td><td>Netherlands Forensic Institute; TU Delft <br /> Netherlands Forensic Institute <br /> TU Delft <br /> Netherlands Forensic Institute</td><td>Utilizing Conversations as a Proxy for Topic: a Study in Forensic Authorship Attribution</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Anne Fleur van Luenen</td><td>Netherlands Forensic Institute</td><td>ASMtransformers: a BERT model for ARM64 assembly</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Heike Pauli <br /> Lukas Latacz <br /> Hugo Van hamme</td><td>KU Leuven <br /> SAY IT Labs <br /> Processing Speech and Images (PSI), KU Leuven; Department of Electrical Engineering (ESAT), KU Leuven</td><td>Cross-lingual age estimation: distinguishing child speech from adult speech</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Bram van Dijk <br /> Marco Spruit</td><td>Leiden University Medical Center</td><td>Welzijn.AI: a System in Development for Monitoring Mental Wellbeing in Dutch Elderly Populations</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Jan Odijk <br /> Martin Kroon <br /> Tijmen Baarda <br /> Ben Bonfil <br /> Sheean Spoel</td><td>Utrecht University</td><td>Automatic Identification of MWEs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Anaïs Tack <br /> Tuba Özturan <br /> Siem Buseyne</td><td>imec research group ITEC, KU Leuven</td><td>Classifying Utterances with Collaborative Problem-Solving Strategies in Student Teamwork Interactions</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Caspar de Jong <br /> Oskar van der Wal <br /> Willem Zuidema</td><td>University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam <br /> Institute for Logic, Language and Computation, University of Amsterdam</td><td>Causal Methods for a (Mechanistic) Understanding of Gender Bias in Dutch Language Models</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Thomas Winters <br /> Stijn Van der Stockt</td><td>KU Leuven <br /> DPG Media</td><td>Evaluating Humor Generation in an Improvisational Comedy Setting</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Reshmi Gopalakrishna Pillai <br /> Antske Fokkens <br /> Wouter van Atteveldt</td><td>Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam</td><td>A Synergic Solution for the Regional Newsrooms: Identifying Regionally Relevant Information for News Stories with LLMs and Knowledge Graphs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Jiahui Liang <br /> Stephan Raaijmakers <br /> Aletta G. Dorst <br /> Jelena Prokic</td><td>Leiden University <br /> Leiden University; TNO <br /> Leiden University <br /> Leiden University</td><td>Using GPT-4 for Conventional Metaphor Detection</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Hans van Halteren</td><td>Radboud University</td><td>Cross-genre and -topic authorship recognition on Dutch human and LLM-generated essays</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Wenwen Guan <br /> Marijn Alta <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>University of Amsterdam</td><td>Automatic Metadiscourse Classification in Learners’ Writing and Speaking with SpanBERT</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Leonidas Zotos <br /> Malvina Nissim <br /> Hedderik van Rijn</td><td>University of Groningen</td><td>Comparing Language Models and Student Strategies for Solving Multiple Choice Questions</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Angel Daza <br /> Ellie Smith <br /> Antske Fokkens</td><td>Netherlands eScience Center <br /> Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam</td><td>Informed Evaluation of Text Analysis Tools</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Rik van Noord</td><td>University of Groningen</td><td>Benchmarking Beyond Translation: The Intrinsically Dutch Compound Noun Challenge for LLMs</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Iris Hendrickx <br /> Stan Vissers <br /> Frank van Meurs</td><td>Centre for Language Studies, Radboud University</td><td>Characteristics of non-native communication in English: The case of English-language lyrics by Dutch artists</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Silvia Stopponi <br /> Saskia Peels-Matthey <br /> Malvina Nissim</td><td>Center for Language and Cognition Groningen, University of Groningen</td><td>Creating a dataset for the evaluation of automatic semantic change detection in Ancient Greek</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Tim Van de Cruys</td><td>KU Leuven</td><td>Do Tomatoes Sing Skyscrapers? The Curious Case of Absurd Text Generation</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Xiaojuan Tan <br /> Jelke Bloem</td><td>Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam <br /> University of Amsterdam</td><td>Predicting the metaphoric potential of words from lexical features</td></tr>
            </tbody>
        </table>
    </div>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="abstracts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Notifications of acceptance for CLIN 34 have been sent out. Find the program here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Abstract submissions now closed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/23/abstract-submission-closed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Abstract submissions now closed" /><published>2024-05-23T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-23T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/05/23/abstract-submission-closed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/23/abstract-submission-closed/"><![CDATA[<div>
Abstract submission for CLIN 34 is now closed! We are pleased to announce we received more than 130 submissions. Notifications of acceptance will be sent out by June 15th 2024.
</div>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="abstracts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract submission for CLIN 34 is now closed! We are pleased to announce we received more than 130 submissions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GPT-NL: Announcing Dominique Blok and Erik de Graaf from TNO as keynote speakers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/14/announcing-tno-keynote/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GPT-NL: Announcing Dominique Blok and Erik de Graaf from TNO as keynote speakers" /><published>2024-05-14T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/05/14/announcing-tno-keynote</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/14/announcing-tno-keynote/"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce that <a href="https://www.dominiqueblok.com/">Dominique Blok</a> and <a href="https://www.tno.nl/nl/over-tno/onze-mensen/erik-graaf/">Erik de Graaf</a> from TNO will host a keynote at CLIN 34 regarding <a href="https://www.tno.nl/en/newsroom/2023/11/netherlands-starts-realisation-gpt-nl/">GPT-NL</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="keynotes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dominique Blok and Erik de Graaf from TNO will host a keynote regarding GPT-NL at CLIN 34!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing Diana Maynard as a keynote speaker</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/20/announcing-diana-maynard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing Diana Maynard as a keynote speaker" /><published>2024-03-20T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-03-20T18:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/20/announcing-diana-maynard</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/20/announcing-diana-maynard/"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce <a href="https://staffwww.dcs.shef.ac.uk/people/D.Maynard/">Diana Maynard</a> as a keynote speaker for CLIN 34!</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="keynotes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to announce Diana Maynard as a keynote speaker for CLIN 34!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Call for abstracts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/15/call-for-abstracts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call for abstracts" /><published>2024-03-15T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-03-15T18:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/15/call-for-abstracts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/15/call-for-abstracts/"><![CDATA[<div>
Abstracts describing work on any aspect of computational linguistics / natural language processing (finished or in progress), are welcome for submission at CLIN 34. Submissions must be written in English, adhere to the 500 word limit, and must be submitted through <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1G2Ee1LUfQdmh2xQz8T46YcR1BXUMuB4q4iuAKq9sp8Q">this web form</a>. Please provide all information requested in the form. 
<br /><br />
The submission deadline is May 22nd 2024 and notifications of acceptance will be sent out on June 15th 2024. Authors of accepted abstracts will have the opportunity to submit a full paper after the conference to CLIN Journal.
</div>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;clin34@leidenuniv.nl&quot;}</name><email>clin34@leidenuniv.nl</email></author><category term="abstracts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Click here for more information.]]></summary></entry></feed>